{
    "id": "25d5245da1364b5c8e8cce28e0b6abf0",
    "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "One day scientists will ......................... find a cure for cancer.",
            "description": "'Be able to' and 'can' can both be used to talk about ability. After will 'can' cannot be used. Only be able to is possible. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "able to",
                "be able to",
                "have been able to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You are interested in the offer, .........................?",
            "description": "We use a negative tag after an affirmative statement. The auxiliary used in the statement is repeated in the question tag. ",
            "answers": [
                "are you",
                "aren't you",
                "do you",
                "don't you"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I had never before met ......................... .",
            "description": "The correct structure is 'so + adjective + a/an + noun'. ",
            "answers": [
                "so kind woman",
                "a so kind woman",
                "so a kind woman",
                "so kind a woman"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know why they decided to split. They were ......................... in love with each other.",
            "description": "Mad is an adjective. Madly is an adverb. We use adverbs to modify verbs. ",
            "answers": [
                "mad",
                "madly",
                "madden",
                "badly"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She was ......................... injured in the crash.",
            "description": "Deadly is an adjective. It goes before a noun. Fatal is also an adjective. Fatally is an adverb. ",
            "answers": [
                "fatal",
                "fatally",
                "deadly"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You can speak .......................... I won’t tell anyone what you say.",
            "description": "Free means without payment. Freely means without restriction.",
            "answers": [
                "free",
                "freely",
                "with freedom"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I very much enjoy ........................ .",
            "description": "The verb enjoy can be followed by a noun/pronoun/-ing form. It cannot be followed by an infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "swim",
                "swimming",
                "to swim"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She would never ......................... if she hadn’t changed jobs.",
            "description": "The sentence is in the type three conditional. Here we use a past perfect in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the result clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have promoted",
                "be promoted",
                "have been promoted"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t trust politicians. I never have, and I ......................... .",
            "description": "Parallel structures are used here. ",
            "answers": [
                "will never",
                "never will",
                "never does",
                "never would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am going to do my exams, and ......................... I am going to study medicine.",
            "description": "After cannot be used alone as an adverb. Instead, we use the expression afterwards. ",
            "answers": [
                "after",
                "afterward",
                "afterwards"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I expected to fail the exam, but I passed ......................... .",
            "description": "After all can mean contrary to what was expected. ",
            "answers": [
                "at all",
                "after all",
                "nevertheless"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was ......................... I was working.",
            "description": "The structure is/am/are etc. + … age is used without a preposition",
            "answers": [
                "at your age",
                "your age",
                "of your age"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}